Guide to the George A. Lindbeck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Collected Materials: Ecumenism, Series VIII
  - Roman Catholic
    - General
      - re: Ecumenism: "Interim Directives for Ecumenical Activities in the Diocese of Bridgeport" by Walter W. Curtis, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 1097)
      - re: Ecumenism: "Ecumenical Collaboration at the Regional, National and Local Levels" in National Conference of Catholic Bishops, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 1098)
      - re: Education: "Recent Roman Catholic Bible Study and Translation" by C. Umhau Wolf in Journal of Bible and Religion, v.29, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 1099)
      - re: Episcopacy: "La sacramentalite de l'Episcopat" by Roberto Masi in L'Osservatore Romano, nd (Box 44, Folder 1100)
      - re: Evangelicals: "An Evangelical Awakening in the Catholic Church?" in Christianity Today; "Reflections on the Question of Evangelical Catholicity" by Gerhard O. Forde, 1973; nd (Box 44, Folder 1101)
      - re: Fiction: "The 'Deputy' Controversy" in Christian Century; "Un signe de contradiction" in L'Osservatore Romano, 1964; 1964 (Box 45, Folder 1102)
      - re: Fiction: "Roman Ordinary" by John L'Heureux in Harper's, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 1103)
      - re: Heresy: "The Kung and Schillebeeckx Cases" by Richard P. McBrien in Catholic Transcript; "Pope John Paul II: His First Year" by Hans Kung in New York Times; "The Kung Case" in Christian Century, 1980; 1979; 1975 (Box 45, Folder 1104)
      - re: Infallibility: "Infallibility as Charism at Vatican I" by Kilian McDonnell; "Infallibility Revisited" by Daniel S. Hamilton in America, nd; 1973 (Box 45, Folder 1105)
      - re: Infallibility: "The Infallible Word" by Harold Lindsell in Christianity Today; "The Vatican Council 1869-1870", 1972; nd (Box 45, Folder 1106)
      - re: Mary/Saints: "Maria et Ecclesia: Acta Congressus Mariologici-Mariani" in Academia Mariana Internationalis; :New Laws for the Causes of theSaints" by Sacred Congregation for the Causes of the Saints", 1960; 1983 (Box 45, Folder 1107)
      - re: Mary/Saints: "The Basement Madonna" by Ernest F. Miller; "Extended Memo on the Veneration of the Saints" by Kilian McDonnell, 1975; nd (Box 45, Folder 1108)
      - re: Ministry: "Razionalismo Esegesi cattolica e Magistero" by Francesco Spadafora in Rovigo; "Free Ministry in the U.S.A." by Gregory Baum in Concilium, 1961; 1974 (Box 45, Folder 1109)
      - re: Papacy: "The Papal Encyclical and French Evangelism" by Jean-Pierre Monsarrat in Christianity and Society; "The Quest of the Theological Sources of the Doctrine of Papal Primacy" by K. Froehlich, 1951; nd (Box 45, Folder 1110)
      - re: Papacy: "The Christocentricity of Pope John Paul II" by John Saward, nd (Box 45, Folder 1111)
      - re: Petrine Office: "The Petrine Office in the Church" by Ernest Henau; "The Catholic Understanding of Office in the Church" by Edward Schillebeeckx; "The Roman View of the Petrine Office in the Church 366-461" (Box 45, Folder 1112)
      - re: Reception: "Zur Hermeneutik und Rezeption des Okumenismusdekretes" by Werner Becker in Dienst der Vermittlung, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 1113)
      - re: Salvation: "Missionary Challenges to the Theology of Salvation" by H. E. Card and Jozef Tomko (Box 45, Folder 1114)
      - re: Sermons: "Sermon prononce le dimanche 20 octobre 1974, dans la cathedrale de St Jean de Lyon" by Jean Willebrands (Box 45, Folder 1115)
      - re: God: "Reward or Loss-Which?" by G.P. Raud in American Seminary of the Bible, nd (Box 45, Folder 1116)
    - Vatican II
      - re: Council: Concilio Ecumenico Vaticano II Documents, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 1117)
      - re: Council: "Das Konzil: Dritte Session", 1962 (Box 45, Folder 1118)
      - re: Council: Miscellaneous (incl. "Reformation und Konzil: gester, heute und morgen" by Hermann Dietzfelbinger; "Laetentur Coeli et Exultet Terra" in Concilio Ecumenico Fiorentino ), 1962; nd (Box 45, Folder 1119)
      - re: Council: Lindbeck's Correspondence/Diary, 1962-64 (Box 45, Folder 1120)
      - re: Council: Lindbeck's Notes, 1962-64 (Box 45, Folder 1121)
      - re: Council: Lindbeck's Reports from and Lectures at Vatican II, 1962-64 (Box 46, Folder 1122)
      - re: Council: Reports of Others (incl. Sven Silen, Gerhard Pedersen), 1962-64 (Box 46, Folder 1123)
      - re: Council: Source Materials, 1962-64 (Box 46, Folder 1124)
      - re: Council: Lectures/Articles (incl. "Excerpts from Talks Delivered to the American Roman Catholic Hierarchy"), 1964 (Box 46, Folder 1125)
      - re: Council: Roster of Delegated Observers and Guests, 1964 (Box 46, Folder 1126)
      - re: Council: Miscellaneous (incl. "What If Vatican II Succeeds?" by Albert C. Outler), 1964 (Box 46, Folder 1127)
      - re: Council: Drafts and Schemas of Decrees, 1963-65 (Box 46, Folder 1128)
      - re: Council: "Decretum de Oecumenismo (Decree on Ecumenism)", 1965 (Box 46, Folder 1129)
      - re: Council: "Pacem in Terris (Peace on Earth)", 1965 (Box 46, Folder 1130)
      - re: Council: "Untruths Contained in Some Official Documents: Constitutions, Decrees, Declarations and Speeches of the Vatican Council" by A. Johnson, 1965 (Box 46, Folder 1131)
      - re: Council: "A Loyola Symposium: The Church Since Vatican II" in Loyola Magazine, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 1132)
      - re: Council: Writings of Rev. James Malone, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 1133)
      - re: Council: Reflections of Laymen, nd (Box 47, Folder 1134)
      - re: Council: Miscellaneous Documents, nd (Box 47, Folder 1135)
      - re: Declaration on Freedom of Religion: "Text of the Declaration on Freedom of Religion Adopted by the Ecumenical Council" in New York Times, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 1136)
      - re: Ecumenism: "Vatican II: Decree on Ecumenism" in Ecumenism 2, 1966 (Box 47, Folder 1137)
      - re: Marriage: "Reform of the Roman Catholic Law on Mixed Marriages" by Erwin Wilkens in Ecumenical Review, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 1138)
      - re: News Coverage: Federal Council of Protestant Churches in Italy, Press and Information Service, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 1139)
      - re: News Coverage: Periodicals (incl. Documentate Centrum ), 1962 (Box 47, Folder 1140)
      - re: News Coverage: Newspaper Clippings, 1962-64 (Box 47, Folder 1141)
      - re: News Coverage: Newspaper Clippings, 1962-64 (Box 47, Folder 1142)
      - re: News Coverage: Periodicals (incl. Religious News Service ), 1963 (Box 47, Folder 1143)
      - re: Women: "Vatican Declaration: Women in the Ministerial Priesthood" in Origins, v.6 n.33, 1977 (Box 47, Folder 1144)
      - Official Documents (incl. Schemata Constitutionum et Decretorum), 1962-65 (Box 48, Folder 1145)
      - Official Documents (incl. De Ecclesia in Mundo Huius Temporis), 1962-65 (Box 49, Folder 1146)
  - Anglican-Roman Catholic
    - "Doctrinal Agreement and Christian Unity: Methodological Considerations", 1972-73 (Box 50, Folder 1147)
    - "The Baltimore Declaration" in Mission and Ministry, v.9 n.4, 1993 (Box 50, Folder 1148)
  - Anglican-Lutheran
    - "Proposed Concordat of Agreement Between the Episcopal Church and the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America", 1991 (Box 50, Folder 1149)
    - "Toward Full Communion Between the Episcopal Church and the Evangelical Lutheran Church in America", 1991 (Box 50, Folder 1150)
  - Judaism
    - "Christian-Jewish Dialogue and the Meaning of the State of Israel" by Abraham J. Heschel in Cross Currents, v. XIX, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 1151)
    - Articles (incl. Church and Synagogue" by W.D. Davies in Christianity and Crisis; "The Jews, Renewal and Ecumenism" by George Lindbeck in Journal of Ecumenical Studies ), 1964; 1965 (Box 50, Folder 1152)
    - Lectures/Articles (incl. "Pragmatic Conditions for Jewish-Christian Theological Dialogue" by Peter Ochs; "Study on Israel: People, Land, State" by Department of Faith and Order of the National Council of Churches and Secretariat for Jewish-Catholic Relations of the National Conference of Catholic Bishops) (Box 50, Folder 1154)
    - Articles (incl. "Israel: People, Land and State: Suggestions for a Theological Evaluation"; "A Response to a Statement Adopted by the Synod of de Hervormede Kerk, the Netherlands" by J. Coert Rylaarsdam), 1967; 1971 (Box 50, Folder 1155)
    - United Christian Council in Israel, 1978 (Box 50, Folder 1156)
  - Multi-Denominational Dialogue
    - re: ACURA: "Fifth Annual Conference at Cornell" in Dialogue on Campus, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 1157)
    - re: Bilateral Consultations: "The Bilateral Consultations Between the Roman Catholic Church in the United States and Other Christian Communions" in Catholic Theological Society of America Report, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 1158)
    - re: Bilateral Consultations: "DTS Free Conference on Bilaterals/Reception"; "A Challenge to Reception: The Unity of the Churches by Hans Fries and Karl Rahner" by William G. Rusch; "Reflections on the Fries-Rahner Proposal Thesis I", 1985 (Box 50, Folder 1159)
    - re: Church: "Bund der Evangelischen Kirchen in der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik", 1969 (Box 50, Folder 1160)
    - re: Church: "Material from the Consultation on Church Union Churches on the Mutual Recognition of Members", 1980-81 (Box 50, Folder 1161)
    - re: Ecumenism: "Ecumenical Relations"; "Prognosen fur die Zukunft des Oekumenismus" by Joseph Ratzinger, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 1162)
    - re: Heresy: Letter Concerning Kung and Schillebeeckx Cases, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 1163)
    - re: Inerrancy: "Baptist: Bill Powell: Inerrancy the Issue" by James C. Hefley in Christianity Today, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1164)
    - re: Missions: "Mouvement Oecumenique et Mission", 1964 (Box 50, Folder 1165)
    - re: National Council of the Churches of Christ: Constitution and Certificate of Incorporation, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 1166)
    - re: Papacy: "Role of the Papacy Studied at Interreligious Conference" in Religious News Service, 1975 (Box 50, Folder 1167)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "Faith and Order Today: Self-Examination and Prospect: The Dialogue with the Church of Rome" by Hans Heinrich Harms; "Tradition and Traditions: Toward an Orthodox Attitude" by Konstantin Bonis, 1962 (Box 50, Folder 1168)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "Eine oekumenische Studie uber die Konzilien der Alten Kirche und ihre Bedeutung fur die heutige okemenische Bewegung", 1963 (Box 50, Folder 1169)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): Fifth World Faith and Order Conference, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 1170)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): Fourth World Conference-Montreal, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 1171)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "Roman Catholic Reactions to Faith and Order Reports", 1963 (Box 51, Folder 1172)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "Tradition, Scripture and Church in Ireanaeus" by E. Flesseman van Leer, 1963 (Box 51, Folder 1173)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "The Point of the Ecumenical Situation" by Roger Mehl; "The Ordained Ministry in Ecumenical Perspective" in Study Encounter, v. VIII n.4, 1963; 1972 (Box 51, Folder 1174)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC):" World Confessional Families and the World Council of Churches: Nairobi and the 1974 Discussion Paper"-London (Box 51, Folder 1175)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "The Teaching Authority of the Church", 1977 (Box 51, Folder 1176)
    - re: World Council of Churches: "Die Kirche, de Kirchen und der Oekumenische Rat der Kirchen" (Box 51, Folder 1177)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): Roster, nd (Box 51, Folder 1178)
    - re: World Council of Churches (WCC): "Scripture, Tradition, and Traditions" (Box 51, Folder 1179)
  - World Religions
    - "Introduction" from Conference on Christian Revelation and non-Christian Religions, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 1180)
    - "Christentum ausserhalb der Kirche?: Zum interconfessionellen Gesprach uber das Verstandnis der Welt" by Ulrich Kuhn in Erneurung der eine Kirche, 1966 (Box 51, Folder 1181)
    - "Die 'Anonymen Christen' Exegetisch Gesehen" by Heinz Kruse, nd (Box 51, Folder 1182)
    - "How Can Non-Christians Find Salvation in Their Own Religions?" by Piet Fransen in Christian Revelation and World Religions (Box 51, Folder 1183)
    - "The World Religions in God's Plan of Salvation" in Christian Revelation and World Religions (Box 51, Folder 1184)
  - Anti-Roman Catholic
    - "Is this Religious Freedom?" translated by J. A. Fernandez in Pro-Ca Digest, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 1185)
    - "Der Antiromische Affekt" by Hans Urs von Balthasaar, nd (Box 51, Folder 1186)
    - "A New Attack Against Catholic Exegesis and Against the Pontifical Biblical Institute" (Box 51, Folder 1187)
    - Pamphlets (incl. "Religion, Politics and the Presidency" by Harold John Ockenga; "Wrong Directions" in Christian Heritage Pamphlets ) (Box 51, Folder 1188)
    - Pamphlets (incl. "'Here I Stand; I Can Do Naught Else; God Help Me. Amen.': Martin Luther, Before the Diet of Worms, April 17, 1521" by A. B. Ost; "The Roman Catholic Bible Has the Answer" in Christian Heritage Pamphlets ) (Box 51, Folder 1189)
  - Evangelical
    - "Evangelicals: Ecumenical Allies" by Richard Quebedeaux in Christianity and Crisis, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 1190)
    - "The Evangelistic Imperative" in Christianity Today, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 1191)
    - "Can Catholics Subscribe to the 'Lausanne Covenant'?" by Joseph M. Connors in America, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 1192)
    - "Evangelism to Communist Lands, Inc." by Haralan Popov in Door of Hope, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 1193)
    - "Others Say...Schaeffer on Scripture" by Francis A. Schaeffer in Christianity Today, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 1194)
    - "Egalitarianism and Scriptural Infallibility" by Harold Lindsell in Chrisitianity Today, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1195)
    - "Who Are the Evangelicals?" in Christianity Today, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1196)
    - "Will Evangelicals Swing the Election?" in Christianity Today, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 1197)
    - "Nottingham '77: Evangelicals Eye Unity" in Christianity Today, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 1198)
    - "Philosophy: The Roots of Vain Deceit" by Norman L. Geisler in Christianity Today, 1977 (Box 51, Folder 1199)
    - "The Shaking Up of Adventism?" in Christianity Today, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 1200)
  - Society and Industry
    - "The Nature and Future of Private Enterprise" by Edwin G. Nourse, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 1201)
    - "Bibliography of Economic and Social Study Material" from National Association of Manufacturers; "Report and Recommendations to Industry of the N.A.M. Commmittee on Cooperation with Churches" from National Industrial Information Committee, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 1202)
    - "Good Industrial Relations" from National Association of Manufacturers; "Annual Report 1943" from National Association of Manufacturers; "Jobs, Freedom, Opportunity" from National Association of Manufacturers, 1943; 1943; 1943 (Box 51, Folder 1203)
    - "Pot of Gold" from General Motors, 1943 (Box 52, Folder 1204)
    - "Victory for Freedom: Industry's Creed" from National Association of Manufacturers; "Fallacies About Our Private Enterprise System" from National Association of Manufacturers; "Cartels" from Research Department of National Association of Manufacturers, 1944; 1944; 1944 (Box 52, Folder 1205)
    - "The Economic Background for Social Action" from National Association of Manufacturers; "The Responsibilites of Victory" from National Association of Manufacturers; "The Public and Industrial Peace: A National Labor Policy to Minimize Industrial Strikes" form National Association of Manufacturers, 1945; 1945; 1945 (Box 52, Folder 1206)
    - "Bibliography of Economic and Social Study Material" from National Association of Manufacturers, 1946 (Box 52, Folder 1207)
    - "'The Secular City'-Ten Years Later" by Harvey Cox in Christian Century, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 1208)
    - "Strife Over Social Concerns" in Christianity Today, 1976 (Box 52, Folder 1209)
    - "The Scope and Limits of SALT" by Richard Burt (Box 52, Folder 1210)
  - World Council of Churches
    - "The Issue of the Filioque Clause in Ecumenical Perspective": Memorandum of a Consultation held at Schloss Klingenthal, 1978 (Box 92, Folder 14)
- Collected Materials: General, nd; Series IX
  - re: Apocalypticism: "Ontology and Ecclesiology in the Apocalypse" by Paul S. Minear in New Testament Studies (Box 53, Folder 1211)
  - re: Art: "Comments on the History of Things" in Shape of Time, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 1212)
  - re: Barth: "Analogy and the Spirit in the Theology of Karl Barth" by H.W. Frei (Box 53, Folder 1213)
  - re: Barth: "Extra Nos-Pro Nobis-In Nobis" by Karl Barth, nd (Box 53, Folder 1214)
  - re: Beatificabile: "Note sur Esse Beatificabile" by Paul Vignaux, nd (Box 53, Folder 1215)
  - re: Beliefs: "The Structure and Criteria of Early Christian Beliefs" by Helmut Koester in Trajectories Through Early Chrisitianity, Fortress Press, 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1216)
  - re: Christ: "Existentiale Interpretation und Anonyme Christlichkeit" by Heinrich Ott in Zeit und Geschichte, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 1217)
  - re: Christ: "Hij is een God van Mensen" translated by Della Couling, Herder and Herder, Inc., 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1218)
  - re: Christ: "Studien zur Christologie" in Theologische Revue, n.2, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 1219)
  - re: Culture: "Acute Problems in Our Culture" in Paperback Sampler, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 1220)
  - re: Culture: "The Cultural Seduction of the Church" by Brendan F. J. Furnish in Christianity Today, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1221)
  - re: Development: "Line and Plummet" by Richard Dickinson, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1222)
  - re: Doctrine: "Religious Assertions and Doctrinal Development" by Anselm Atkins in Theological Studies, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 1223)
  - re: Doctrine: "Religious Assertions and Doctrinal Development" by Anselm Atkins in Theological Studies, 1966 (Box 53, Folder 1224)
  - re: Doctrine: "The Doctrine of Analogy and Recent Analytic Philosophy: A Historical Sketch" by Al Martin (Box 53, Folder 1225)
  - re: Doctrine: "Progres ou Structurations des Doctrines?" by J.P. Jossua in Revue des Sciences e Philosophiques, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1226)
  - re: Dogma: "Dogma as an Ecumenical Problem" by Avery Dulles in Theological Studies, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1227)
  - re: Enlightenment: "Religion and the Enlightenments or Joshing Mr. Rorty" by Richard John Neuhaus, 1990 (Box 53, Folder 1228)
  - re: Eschatology: "The Interpretation of Eschatology" by Edward Schillebeeckx in Coniclium, v.41, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1229)
  - re: Faith: "What Faith Is" by P. Tillich in Dynamics of Faith (Box 53, Folder 1230)
  - re: Hartford Affirmations: "The Hartford Affirmations" in Christianity Today, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 1231)
  - re: Hebrew: untitled, nd (Box 53, Folder 1232)
  - re: Religion: "Sind Religionen Heilswege?" in Stimmen der Zeit (Box 53, Folder 1233)
  - re: Human: "Answering for the Self, the Elizabethans' Sense of Divine and Human Justice" by D.W. Harding in TLS, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1234)
  - re: Incarnation: "Space, Time, and Incarnation" by Thomas F. Torrance, 1969 (Box 53, Folder 1235)
  - re: Liberation: "Exodus and Exile: The Two Faces of Liberation" by John H. Yoder in Cross Currents, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 1236)
  - re: Lonergan: "Christ as Subject: A Reply" by Bernard Lonergann in Gregorianum, v. XL n.2, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 1237)
  - re: Lonergan: "De Methodo Theologiae" by Bernard Lonergan, 1962 (Box 53, Folder 1238)
  - re: Lonergan: "Foundations of Theology", 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1239)
  - re: Lonergan: "The Lonergan Explosion: Insight and Oversights" by Michael Novak in Commonweal, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 1240)
  - re: Lonergan: "Phenomenon of Bernard Lonergan" by Bernard J. Tyrell in America, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 1241)
  - re: Lonergan: "Lonergan's 'Method'" by Richard M. Liddy in America, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 1242)
  - re: Lonergan: "Method and Sensibility: Novak's Debt to Lonergan" by David Burrell in JAAR, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 1243)
  - re: Lonergan: "Philosophy of God, and Theology: The Relationship Between Philosophy of God and the Functional Specialty, Systematics" by Bernard Lonergan, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 1244)
  - re: Lonergan: "Intentionality in Edmund Husserl and Bernard Lonergan" by William F.J. Ryan in International Philosophical Quarterly, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 1245)
  - re: Lonergan: "Cognitional Structure" in Collection, nd (Box 53, Folder 1246)
  - re: Lonergan: "Insight and the Meno" by Ernan McMullin (Box 53, Folder 1247)
  - re: Lonergan: "Lonergan's Theory of Knowledge and the Social Sciences" by Hugo Meynell (Box 53, Folder 1248)
  - re: Luther: "Luther's Theology of the Cross" by Regin Prenter in Lutheran World, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 1249)
  - re: Luther: "The Relationship Between Salvation and Ethics in Luther's Theology" by Hans O. Tiefel in Lutheran Quarterly, v.25, 1973 (Box 53, Folder 1250)
  - re: Metaphysics: "A Rough Sketch of Post-Skeptical Metaphysical Thinking" by John A. Hutchison, nd (Box 53, Folder 1251)
  - re: Paul: "The Apostle Paul and the Introspective Conscience of the West" by Krister Stendahl in Harvard Theological Review (Box 53, Folder 1252)
  - re: Prophecy: "Prophecy and Fanaticism" by Malcolm L. Diamond in Christianity and Crisis, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1253)
  - re: Protestantism: "United Presbyterians: A Crisis of Confidence" in Christianity Today, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 1254)
  - re: Protestantism: "Zur Theologie Religionen im Protestantismus" by Peter Beyerhaus, nd (Box 53, Folder 1255)
  - re: Rahner: "Die Taufe der Weltreligionen: Bemerkungen zu einer Theorie Karl Rahners" by P. Leo Elders in Theologie u. Glaube, v.55, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 1256)
  - re: Rahner: "Die Enzyklika als reformable Lebrausserung" by Karl Rahner in Stimmen der Zeit, 1968 (Box 53, Folder 1257)
  - re: Rahner: "Zum Begriff der Unfehlbarkeit in der katholischen Theologie" by Karl Rahner in Stimmen der Zeit, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 1258)
  - re: Rahner: "Zum Begriff der Unfehlbarkeit in der katholischen Theologie" by Karl Rahner in Stimmen der Zeit, 1970 (Box 53, Folder 1259)
  - re: Rahner: "The Death of Jesus and the Closing of Revelation" by Karl Rahner, 1975 (Box 53, Folder 1260)
  - re: Rahner: "Grace for a New Generation" by John P. Galvin in Commonweal, 1985 (Box 53, Folder 1261)
  - re: Rahner: "Nature, Grace, and Experience: Karl Rahner's Theology of Human Transformation" by J.A. DiNoia, 1992 (Box 53, Folder 1262)
  - re: Rahner: "Experience of the Spirit: Source of Theology" by Karl Rahner in Theological Investigations, nd (Box 53, Folder 1263)
  - re: Rahner: "Faith and Ministry" by Karl Rahner in Theological Investigations (Box 54, Folder 1264)
  - re: Rahner: "God and Revelation" by Karl Rahner in Theological Investigations (Box 54, Folder 1265)
  - re: Rahner: "Karl Rahner" by J.A. DiNoia, nd (Box 54, Folder 1266)
  - re: Rahner: "On Being a Symbol: An Appraisal of Karl Rahner" by James J. Buckley in Theological Studies, nd (Box 54, Folder 1267)
  - re: Rahner: "Replik" by Karl Rahner in Stimmen der Zeit (Box 54, Folder 1268)
  - re: Resurrection: "Joy and the Cross" edited by C. DuQuoc, 1968 (Box 54, Folder 1269)
  - re: Resurrection: "Resurrection as Hope" by J. Moltmann in Religion, Revolution, and the Future, 1969 (Box 54, Folder 1270)
  - re: Resurrection: "The Resurrection as the Emergence of the Body of Christ", nd (Box 54, Folder 1271)
  - re: Roman Catholicism: "Towards a Strong Germany" in Paperback Sampler, 1964 (Box 54, Folder 1272)
  - re: Roman Catholicism: "Theologie der Religionen" by Erwin Fahlbusch, nd (Box 54, Folder 1273)
  - re: Social: "The Difficulty of Interpreting Science" by B.C. Brookes in Listener, 1959 (Box 54, Folder 1274)
  - re: Social: "Theological Reflections on Pluralism" by Hans Frei in Theological Studies, 1967 (Box 54, Folder 1275)
  - re: Social: "The Limits of Social Policy" by Nathan Glazer in Commentary, 1971 (Box 54, Folder 1276)